<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Track-rsses on Kiwipedia</title>
    <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Track-rsses on Kiwipedia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 21:24:31 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mokoroa Falls and Goldie Bush loop</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/mokoroa-falls-and-goldie-bush-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 21:24:31 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/mokoroa-falls-and-goldie-bush-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great loop track going down througg regenerating native forrest to two beautiful waterfalls. then following the stream with couple of swimming holes and return back via steep climb through bush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 40 minutes drive from Auckland CBD and when you are getting closer the road becomes windier and narrower, then it turns to gravel for couple of kilometres. At the end of Horsman road there is a little carpark with no facilities. get on Mokoroa Falls track which goes steadily down through lovely native forrest, after 20 minutes of walk you end up on the viewing platform - you can take great pictures of the main Mokoroa Falls from here. But there is another smaller waterfall just under your feet. So take the steps down and enjoy great view of both waterfalls in the little canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then follow the stream which you will need to cross several times on your way down. There are some beautiful swimming holes you can enjoy to dip in. After another 20 minutes you will arrive to walking bridge, turn left, cross the bridge and continue climbing up via the Goldi Bush walkaway. in 30 minutes you will again end up on Mokora Falls track, so just turn right and get back to carpark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goldie Bush and Mokoroa Stream loop</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/goldie-bush-and-mokoroa-stream-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 19:38:37 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/goldie-bush-and-mokoroa-stream-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great walking or running track along stream, to the top of two wonderfull waterfalls and then back through regenerating native bush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This track is composite of 3 different tracks - Goldie Bush Walkway, Mokoroa Falls track and Mokoroa Stream track. It starts at western entry of Goldie Bush Walkway at Constable Road, Muriwai which is approximately 45km from the central Auckland. There is a little carpark and lond drop toilet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After approximately 1km the track splits so be careful and keep on Goldie Bush walkway and don&amp;rsquo;t follow the Hillary trail. Then you will reach a little bridge where the loop starts - you can either turn left and follow the Mokoroa Stream track up to Waterfalls first, or you can cross the bridge, keep following the Goldie Bush Walkway up to hill and then return back via Mokora Falls track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s better take the first option as the stream track could be slippery and muddy after rains and it&amp;rsquo;s always best to go uphill in such terrain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mokoroa Falls Track</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/mokoroa-falls-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 19:38:37 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/mokoroa-falls-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two beautiful waterfalls just 40 minutes drive from Auckland - perfect spot for picnic or swim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just head to Bethells beach but turn right to Horsman road and continue till very end where is little carpark (could be really full especially on sunny days so be prepared to carefully park along the road). There are no tilets or other facilities at the carpark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The track to falls is well maintained by DOC and after 30 minutes walking through young Kauri and Kanuka/Manuka forest you end up on top viewing platform from where you can see the Mokoroa Falls.
There is set of timber steps you can take to get down to the bottom of falls where you can finely see the Houheria falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lagoon at the bottom of walls is not very suitable for swimming but you can follow the stream and you&amp;rsquo;ll find perfect swimming hole with little cascade.
From here you can return the same direction back tpo carpark or follow the stream further via Mokoroa Stream track and return back through Goldie bush Walkway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodfellow track</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/goodfellow-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 21:30:50 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/goodfellow-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short but beautiful track connects Fairy Falls track and Old Couch road - both roughly in middle of their length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its well formed and reasonably dry, with two steeper areas with timber steps. It takes you through native bush and little stream crossing, up couple of natural stone steps in the rock wall and further up the ridge with tall groups of big Kauri trees with great views to surrounding hills of Waitakere ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a perfect way to make a loop from Fairy Falls track - from either Mountain road or Scenic drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy falls and Goodfellow track loop</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/fairy-falls-and-goodfellow-track-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 21:15:08 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/fairy-falls-and-goodfellow-track-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An ideal 1 hour long loop walk along stream, waterfalls and through the kauri forrest with great views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Park at the little carpark on Mountain road - take care when driving as the road is windy and narrow - at some time there is just one lane for both directions. The preferred way is to head to Fairy Falls first, then climb all steps up along the stream and water halls and somewhere in the middle of Fairy Falls track turn right to Goodfellow track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walk will take you slightly down and then through couple of series of steps up to ridge where you can enjoy great view to Auckland CBD and surrounding hills. At the end of the Goodfellow track turn right to Old Coach Road and descend back to carpark. This part of trek can be bit muddy so watch your steps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy falls and Old coach road loop</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/fairy-falls-and-old-coach-road-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 23:00:13 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/fairy-falls-and-old-coach-road-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little bit longer (but still ideal for families or after work run/walk) loop track created from Fairy Falls track and Old Coach road track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start either from Scenic drive or for Mountain road. If you park your car on Scenic drive and you rather walk up the falls then take the Old Coach road track first and then come back through Fairy Falls tracks. Or park on Mountain road and do first the Fairy Falls and then come back via Old Coach road track. It&amp;rsquo;s all up to you but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s better to see the waterfalls on return rather then as a first attraction :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget then you can also use the Goodfellow track to shorten the loop if you wish to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lower Waipapa River track</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/far-north/lower-waipapa-river-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 22:32:08 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/far-north/lower-waipapa-river-track/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy Falls Track</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/fairy-falls-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 20:11:21 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/auckland/fairy-falls-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great track with fair amount of steps - perfect in summer when you can cool down in one of many swimming holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start either from the Scenic drive road and then go down to the bottom of waterfall and then walk up back again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can drive up narrow and windy Mountain road and walk up to base of the waterfall from the other side (recomended option). The track from here is well-formed but you would need to cross shallow stream few times (you can usually cross without getting wet). You will be rewarded with lovely native New Zealand bush with Nikau palms and couple of Kauri trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make this track a loop and return via Old Couch Road track or go through Goodfellow track when climb all steps up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wairakau stream track</title>
      <link>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/far-north/wairakau-stream-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 20:11:21 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kiwipedia.nz/track/far-north/wairakau-stream-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beautiful medium grade track close to Whangaroa harbour, takes you trough native forrest, valley, couple of stream crossing to a DOC hut on sea shore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start of the track is at the end of Campbell road at Totara North. You can leave you car parked there and start climbing up steep and after rain pretty muddy old farm road. After 20 minutes you&amp;rsquo;ll see a sign to Wairaka stream. Descent through native forrest to lovely valley with stream where you will need to cross it couple of times (crossings are shallow but there are great swimming holes too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep going until you reach the DOC hut but don&amp;rsquo;t get in if you didn&amp;rsquo;t book it - you will find toilet close by. Now you can either go back, continue to Duke&amp;rsquo;s Nose (only for fit people as it involves a real rock climbing with ropes up to 30 metres) or you could book a water taci and enjoy nice ride trough Whangaroa harbour back to Totara North.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>